

Mohammad Perwaze

C/O Kutubuddin Ansari, Behind Chandauli RTO Office, Chandauli 9953170797 | perwaze@gmail.com

Objective

M.Tech in Thermal Engineering and B.Tech in Mechanical Engineering with 1+ years of industrial experience and 3+ years of experience in 2D and 3D drafting/modeling. I am looking for an opportunity in a reputable organisation where I can put my expertise and talents to good use, as well as a chance to progress in terms of knowledge and professional development.

Experience

• **G. K. Auto** 1/06/2015 - 15/07/2015

Intern

- 1. Observation and Monitoring of casting of clutch plates.
- 2. Preparation of 3D models in Creo Parametric.
- 3. Testing of product at different stages.
- · LG Electronics India Pvt. Ltd.

08/10/2020 - 30/06/2021

Research and Development Engineer

- 1. Preparation of mockup in UG NX and testing it on real parts.
- 2. 3D audit of split and Window air conditioners.
- 3. Assembly line monitoring.
- 4. Detection and elimination of defects for smooth production.
- Goldrush Capital Services Pvt. Ltd.

10/01/2022 - Present

2010

Technical Manager

- 1. Provide technical support to various banks related to the projects in which the banks have invested.
- 2. Preparation of quarters report for physical and financial progress.
- 3. Audit of plant & machinery.

Education

•	Thapar Institute of Engineering and Technology Master of Engineering : Thermal Engineering 9.44	2021
•	VIT East, Jaipur B.Tech: Mechanical Engineering 71.5	2017
•	Delhi Public School Intermediate 68.7	2012

Skills

8.8

- AutoCAD 2D
- Creo Parametric

 Delhi Public School High School

· Siemens NX

- · Ansys Fluent
- Microsoft Excel
- · Microsoft PowerPoint
- · Microsoft Word

Projects

· Thermal modeling and performance comparison of active and passive solar stills

Thermal modeling and comparison study of photovoltaic thermal compound parabolic collector, photovoltaic thermal flat plate collector coupled with single slope solar still and single slope passive solar still. Energy balance of individual components of a solar still is done and a MATLAB code has been prepared for individual model. Comparison of the three models has been done on the basis of various parameters such as distillate output, thermal efficiency, exergy and some other parameters.

• Domestic Electrolux Refrigeration System

Domestic electrolux refrigeration system: A working model of a domestic electrolux refrigeration system also known as three fluid system was fabricated. The refrigeration system was integrated with a solar panel to provide the energy input.

Energy Harvesting

Energy harvesting system: A small energy harvesting device to convert mechanical vibrations into electricity using piezoelectric crystals was fabricated. The device was used to convert the mechanical vibrations of a lathe machine into electricity.

Exams Qualified

GATE 2017

Mechanical Engineering Score 483

Registration number: ME17S23031218

• GATE 2019

Mechanical Engineering Score 385

Registration number: ME19S25034118